<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on test site hugo</title>
    <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on test site hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 10:46:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay What is Psychology and Who Are Psychologists?</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-what-is-psychology-and-who-are-psychologists/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 10:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-what-is-psychology-and-who-are-psychologists/</guid>
      <description>Psychology is an extensive field of scientific studies from behaviors to mental processing (Zimbardo et. all, 2010, p.2). Psychology is also not to be confused with “common sense facts”, nor should it be considered only speculation. Psychology follows an empirical approach based on observations as well as scientific research (Zimbardo et. all, 2010, p.3). Often in our culture we see “factual” information being shown as proven scientifically, when in reality is pseudopsychology, or psychological findings that are falsely presented as scientific (Zimbardo et.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Approaches In Psychology Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/two-approaches-in-psychology-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 02:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/two-approaches-in-psychology-essay/</guid>
      <description>Two Approaches In Psychology
In 1900, Sigmund Freud, a neurologist living in Vienna, first published his psychoanalytic theory of personality in which the unconscious mind played a crucial role. Freud combined the then current cognitive notions of consciousness, perception and memory with ideas of biologically based instincts, to make a bold new theory of psychodynamics. Freud&amp;rsquo;s theory, which forms the basis of the psychodynamic approach, represented a challenge and a major alternative to behaviourism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay on Clinical Psychology</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 18:45:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Clinical psychology aims to understand, treat and prevent psychological distress and dysfunction thus to encourage good health, good adaptive thinking and a healthy lifestyle. People working in this field research into mental dysfunction suffered by the patients, assess their cognitive state of mind and perform psychotherapy to decrease the psychological symptoms and/ or the underlying causes.
There are many sub divisions of therapies focusing on different routes of cure/prevention. Biologically, chemotherapy and psychosurgeries are available; but below I will discuss the treatments available psychologically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Objective Psychology and Psychoanalysis Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/objective-psychology-and-psychoanalysis-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 10:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/objective-psychology-and-psychoanalysis-essay/</guid>
      <description>1. Objective psychology and psychoanalysis have much in common. Wulff compares these studies on page two hundred and fifty eight by stating “both reject unaided introspection as a means of gathering fundamental data.” In other words, in neither psychoanalysis nor objective psychology, can a person take an observation made from themselves about themselves and consider it fundamental data. Another similarity would be “that human conduct is the outcome of complexly determined casual events that lie outside awareness” (258).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical Psychology Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/clinical-psychology-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 02:42:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/clinical-psychology-essay/</guid>
      <description>Clinical Psychology
Psychology is an extraordinarily diverse field with hundreds of career paths. Some specialties, like treating the mentally ill, are familiar to most. Others, like helping with the design of advanced computer systems or studying memory, are less well-known. What psychologists have in common is a shared interest in mind and behavior. In their work they draw on an ever-expanding body of scientific knowledge about how humans think, act, and feel, and apply the information to their special areas of expertise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compare ; Contrast Two Approaches to Psychology</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/compare-contrast-two-approaches-to-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 18:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/compare-contrast-two-approaches-to-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Psychology is a discipline that involves monitoring mental processes and behaviour scientifically. Psychologists try to delve into the basic functions of a person and animals cerebral activity. This usually involves studying relationships, emotions, personality and many more areas of a person or animals day to day life. Psychology tends to steer towards finding reasons for a person or animals actions in an attempt to resolve them.
There are many different sub - fields of psychology, however it is possible to draw similarities and differences to all aspects of these fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay on Social Psychology in Fight Club</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-social-psychology-in-fight-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-social-psychology-in-fight-club/</guid>
      <description>Deinviduation and Attraction in Fight Club Fight Club is a complex movie in that the two main characters are just two sides of the same person. Edward Norton’s character is the prototypical conformist consumer working a morally questionable office job to feed his obsession with material possessions. He works as a recall coordinator for a “major car company” and applies a formula based on profitability, rather than safety, to determine the necessity of a recall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay on  The Psychology of Parenting Styles</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-the-psychology-of-parenting-styles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 02:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-the-psychology-of-parenting-styles/</guid>
      <description>The Psychology of Parenting Styles
Would you have come out different if your parents used a different parenting style? If you are considered “cool” now could you have come out a nerd if your parents would have used a different parenting style? “Parenting style is one of the primary determinants of your child’s outcome whether he succeeds, achieves, meets the challenges, flounders, gives up, or runs from or fails in handling life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Statistics and Psychology Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/research-statistics-and-psychology-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 18:36:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/research-statistics-and-psychology-essay/</guid>
      <description>Since the beginning of time research and statistics have exercised a vital role in psychology. In this succinct writing an elaboration of how research and statistics are utilized in psychology is revealed. Furthermore, the how and why of such components are expounded herein and a detailed look at primary and secondary data are exposed.
Research, statistics, primary, and secondary data are imperative in psychological analysis. Implementing each of these variants in psychological research may prove beneficial to the researcher when properly appropriated in psychological exploration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay on 50 First Dates Psychology Analysis</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-50-first-dates-psychology-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 10:35:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-50-first-dates-psychology-analysis/</guid>
      <description>50 First Dates
In the movie 50 First Dates one of the main characters suffers from the severe condition of anterograde amnesia. The movie is about Henry Roth who is a wildlife veterinarian in Hawaii, meeting Lucy Whitmore a woman who has a short-term memory loss from an auto accident a year earlier. Henry meets Lucy at a local cafe and takes her out on a date. Henry falls in love with Lucy, but there is one problem when she awakens in the morning, she can&amp;rsquo;t remember him or anything that happened that day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elements of Psychology and Sociology in The Lord of the Flies</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/elements-of-psychology-and-sociology-in-the-lord-of-the-flies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 02:34:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/elements-of-psychology-and-sociology-in-the-lord-of-the-flies/</guid>
      <description>Elements of Psychology and Sociology in The Lord of the Flies
In viewing the aspects of the island society, the author William Golding&amp;rsquo;s Lord of the Flies as a symbolic microcosm of society. He chooses to set the children alone in an unsupervised world, leaving them to learn ‘ the ways of the world’ in a natural setting first hand. Many different perspectives can also be considered. Golding&amp;rsquo;s island of marooned youngsters becomes a microcosm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay on The Study of Psychology and Christianity</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-the-study-of-psychology-and-christianity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 18:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-the-study-of-psychology-and-christianity/</guid>
      <description>The study of psychology and Christianity has been known to be at odds over the past several decades. Many believe that Christianity and Psychology cannot mix or intertwine. They believe a person can only believe in one but not both. In this essay I will discuss what the integration view entails in reference to psychology and Christianity. I will then discuss the major objectives that can arise from this view and follow by the counter objectives and core strengths of this view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethics in Psychology: A Reflection</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/ethics-in-psychology-a-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/ethics-in-psychology-a-reflection/</guid>
      <description>Early on in a psychology students&amp;rsquo; career, he or she is urged to abide by specific guidelines governing his or her behavior to ensure that he or she acts in an ethical manner. A student that has a lax attitude about cutting and pasting words from the web will later have trouble understanding why using the research of others and citing it as your own is unethical when he or she is a graduate student (Landrum &amp;amp; Davis 2012: 179).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychology/clockwork Orange Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/psychologyclockwork-orange-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 02:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/psychologyclockwork-orange-essay/</guid>
      <description>A Clockwork Orange is a film about a wild and troubled young lad Alex. Alex and his friends (droogs) get a high from inflicting harm upon others. They commit random acts of robbery and rape around London. Alex, as the ringleader, eventually gets caught and is sent to prison. It is in prison that scientists study Alex’s violent behavior. Scientists believed that through special training or a program that his evil ways could be fixed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Relationship between Psychology and Movies Essay example</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/the-relationship-between-psychology-and-movies-essay-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 18:29:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/the-relationship-between-psychology-and-movies-essay-example/</guid>
      <description>Movies are most of the time related to a human being’s life. Movies apply psychology to their plots. For example, movies like the StepMom directed by Chris Columbus, and Good Will Hunting directed by Gus Van Sant show us that psychology is part of our lives in a day to day base. It could go from a divorce to a person who is scared to take a step in life. The textbook, Psychology: Core Concept, by Philip G.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay on A Case Study of Ethics in Psychology</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-a-case-study-of-ethics-in-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 10:28:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-a-case-study-of-ethics-in-psychology/</guid>
      <description>In this case, the psychologist is presented with several ethical issues which could cause harm to the client. The first ethical issue that arose in this case is the potential for a role conflict. The psychologist and Mr. Hartwig had contact prior to the development of a therapeutic relationship when the psychologist bought a car from Mr. Hartwig. It may not be enough that the brief, informal relationship ended. The psychologist must assess the dimensions of the previous relationship from the viewpoint of the client as well as his/her own personal feelings (Koocher &amp;amp; Keith-Spiegel, 2008).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay on The Psychology of King Oedipus</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-the-psychology-of-king-oedipus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 02:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-the-psychology-of-king-oedipus/</guid>
      <description>Oedipus Rex, an ancient Greek tragedy authored by the playwright Sophocles, includes many types of psychological phenomena. Most prominently, the myth is the source of the well-known term Oedipal complex, coined by psychologist Sigmund Freud in the late 1800s. In psychology, “complex” refers to a developmental stage. In this case the stage involves the desire of males, usually ages three to five, to sexually or romantically posses their mother, and the consequential resentment of their fathers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Psychology?</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/what-is-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 18:26:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/what-is-psychology/</guid>
      <description>From about 1930 to1970, the definition of psychology changed with dealing more with the scientific study of behavior. From about 1970 on, psychology was defined as the scientific study of behavior and mental processes. However, according to nowadays definition of psychology, it could be defined as the study of the behavior and human mind. Factors which influencing our behavior include physical, emotions, thoughts and social. It can help to solve humans’ problems if we have a complete understanding of the above factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legal Issues Associated With Clinical Psychology</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/legal-issues-associated-with-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 10:25:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/legal-issues-associated-with-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>What are at least two legal issues associated with clinical psychology? What impact do these issues have on the field of clinical psychology?
Psychological testing in the workplace is a legal issue that is associated with clinical psychology. The information gathered from psychological testing can be used against the candidate. Confidentiality issues are in conflict when the legal requirements of a court contradict the Ethics Code of the APA (Plante, 2005).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developmental Psychology:  Attachment Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/developmental-psychology-attachment-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 02:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/developmental-psychology-attachment-essay/</guid>
      <description>Attachment is the formation of a two-way emotional bond between a child and an adult caregiver. It is an important part of developmental psychology, which is concerned with reasons and causes for human behaviour, addressing both nurture and nature aspects of childrearing. John Bowlby (1907-1990) is a key psychologist involved in the studies and theories concerning attachment. He summarised his point and the reason for attachment as follows:
Based on the above, this essay intends to focus on Bowlby’s work which set out to discover links between early separation and later maladjustment through his ‘maternal deprivation hypothesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adolescence: Developmental Psychology and Social Work Practice</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/adolescence-developmental-psychology-and-social-work-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 18:23:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/adolescence-developmental-psychology-and-social-work-practice/</guid>
      <description>Module Title: Human Growth and Behaviour.
Assessment Title:
What are the advantages and disadvantages of viewing behaviour through the life-span perspective for social practise?
ADOLESCENCE
The author’s aim is to outline the advantages as well as disadvantages in adolescence behaviour and human development processes across people life span, and particular adolescence. This essay will look at the different models, theories of social work and the factors that may have influence social work practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empirical Methods and Psychology Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/empirical-methods-and-psychology-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 10:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/empirical-methods-and-psychology-essay/</guid>
      <description>A debate rages in psychology. It is not one of the usual kind, dwelling on a specific aspect of the mind or a new drug, but a controversy dealing with the very foundations of psychology. The issue is determining how psychologists should treat patients and on what psychologists base their choices. Some feel that they must be empirically-supported treatments, treatments backed by hard data and scientifically supported. Others feel that this standard for treatments is much too confining for the complex field of psychology and that many good treatments cannot be backed by hard data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychology&#39;s Influence on Nursing Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/psychologys-influence-on-nursing-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 02:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/psychologys-influence-on-nursing-essay/</guid>
      <description>As defined by Mason and Whitehead, psychology is a branch of biological science which focuses on the study of conscious life in its origin (66). Mason and Whitehead go on to argue that conscious life refers to the experiences of the individual and origins refer to the particular group or issue being reviewed: e.g., child, adult, abnormal or animal (66-7). A basic examination of the definition of psychology demonstrates that the practice is one that requires understanding of the human experience and behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Psychology of Religion: Views from Sigmund Freud Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/the-psychology-of-religion-views-from-sigmund-freud-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 18:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/the-psychology-of-religion-views-from-sigmund-freud-essay/</guid>
      <description>Sigmund Freud was a psychologist known as the ‘father of psychoanalysis’ who believed that our sense of moral understanding is a result of the conditioning of a growing being.
He argued the human mind or ‘psyche’ is split into three parts; the id, which contains basic and primitive, desires e.g. hunger, thirst and lust; the ego, which involves perceptions of the external world that makes us aware of the ‘reality principle,’ one’s most outward aspect of our personality, and the super-ego, which contains the conscience that punishes bad behaviours with guilt, and the ego-ideal that praises good actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay on Color Psychology</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-color-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:21:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-color-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Color Psychology
Like death and taxes, there is no escaping color. It is ubiquitous. Yet what does it all mean? Why are people more relaxed in green rooms? Why do weightlifters do their best in blue gyms?
It is a well-known fact that color influences mood and feeling in common experience, however, the field of color psychology is still not well understood. Research on the psychological aspects of color is difficult for the mere reason that human emotions are not very stable and the psychic make-up of human beings varies from person to person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay on Psychology Theories and Self-Reflection</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-psychology-theories-and-self-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 02:19:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-psychology-theories-and-self-reflection/</guid>
      <description>Running Head: PSYCHOLOGY THEORIES AND SELF-REFLECTION
1
Psychology Theories and Self-Reflection
PSYCHOLOGY THEORIES AND SELF-REFLECTION Psychology Theories and Self-Reflection Introduction “Scientific psychology has four basic goals: to describe, explain, predict, and change behaviour and mental processes through the use of scientific methods” (Carpenter &amp;amp; Huffman, 2008, p. 5). The goal of this paper is not to debate the psychological perspectives, but to give a general focus on three of the more dominant psychological theories, by describing and explaining how the theories relate to personal life experiences, which, in turn, will enable the reader to understand the theories in a more practical way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychology of Drug Abuse Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/psychology-of-drug-abuse-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 18:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/psychology-of-drug-abuse-essay/</guid>
      <description>Understanding the Psychology of Drug Abuse
Drug abuse is on the rise. While the use of drugs like cocaine and heroin is in a state of decline in certain parts of the world, prescription drugs abuse is on the rise (UNODC, 2013). Prescription drugs that were prescribed with the intention to do well are now one of the leading causes of self-harm. Drug abuse has no gender or social class, it can affect people regardless of social status and wealth, and now more than ever we need to understand the reason behind the abuse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Child Psychology Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/child-psychology-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 10:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/child-psychology-essay/</guid>
      <description>Child Psychology
Introduction
Psychology involves studying the mental functioning and general behaviors of both humans and animals. Social behavior and mental functioning of an individual are explained by exploring the neurological and physiological processes. These include emotions, cognition, perception, motivation, attention, brain functioning and personality. Child psychology is as well stated to be the application of psychological techniques to children where it involves carrying out research on mental states and development of children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freud&#39;s Contributions To The Field of Psychology Essay example</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/freuds-contributions-to-the-field-of-psychology-essay-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 02:16:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/freuds-contributions-to-the-field-of-psychology-essay-example/</guid>
      <description>Sigmund Freud was a pioneer within the field of psychology who developed multiple theories that introduced the world to the inner meanings of the human unconscious. He created the theory of psychoanalysis, which allowed him to enter the world of the unconscious mind. He also proposed that humans go through a transition of various psychosexual stages, each level containing a different drive and desire. These urges were governed by the three components of the mind: the id, the ego, and the superego.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Behaviorist and Cognitive Approaches to Psychology Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/the-behaviorist-and-cognitive-approaches-to-psychology-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 18:15:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/the-behaviorist-and-cognitive-approaches-to-psychology-essay/</guid>
      <description>The Behaviorist and Cognitive Approaches to Psychology
In this essay I am going to explore two of the major approaches to Psychology, Cognitive theories and Behaviorist theories. I will discuss in some detail the two approaches, state how they compare and illustrate the similarities and the differences between them.
John Watson, one of the founders of Behaviorism, based his theories on the principles of learning outlined by Pavlov who suggested the theory known as Classical Conditioning; he trained dogs to salivate whenever he rang a bell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brave New World - Psychology Aspect Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/brave-new-world-psychology-aspect-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 10:14:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/brave-new-world-psychology-aspect-essay/</guid>
      <description>A big theme in the book Brave New World by Aldous Huxley is the idea of psychology as a means to control the masses and by default society. Psychology is a very broad subject that covers many opinions and ideas. We’re going to cover five psychologists who come from either the psychoanalytic or behaviorist section of psychology. These theories and beliefs they have convey the messages and ideas of control, sleep teaching, and conditioning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive Psychology Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/cognitive-psychology-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 02:13:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/cognitive-psychology-essay/</guid>
      <description>Cognitive Psychology
Psychology is defined as the study of mind, emotion and behaviour. One major perspective within psychology is known as cognitive psychology, which is primarily concerned with the explanation of thought processes through the development of theoretical mental systems. Cognitivism is somewhat broad in it’s approaches to psychology and only linked in it’s goal to create hypothetical mental structures to explain behaviour (“History &amp;amp; Scope Of Psychology”).
The exact origins of cognitivism are difficult to pinpoint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay  Psychology of Dreams</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-psychology-of-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 18:13:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-psychology-of-dreams/</guid>
      <description>Psychology of Dreams
To many people, dreams are the thoughts that occur while sleeping, having almost mystic qualities. For millennia the significance of dreams has escaped even the brightest of philosophers and intellectuals. Many people have speculated about why people dream and what meanings the dreams have but in recent times two theories have gained credibility in answering those questions. The first theory is Sigmund Freuds and the other is known as the cognitive theory of dreams also known as biological determinism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy A social psychology final paper</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/easy-a-social-psychology-final-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 10:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/easy-a-social-psychology-final-paper/</guid>
      <description>Easy A
12/6/13
SOPS 101
Professor Wight
The movie I chose was Easy A because there are many psychological concepts this movie that relate to real-life events and it covers many theories we learned about in this class. Easy A was released in 2010 and directed by Will Gluck. It’s about a teenage girl named Olive who accidentally admits to her friend Rhi that she was having sexual relations with boys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Psychology: Characteristics, Motives, and Situationism</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/social-psychology-characteristics-motives-and-situationism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 02:11:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/social-psychology-characteristics-motives-and-situationism/</guid>
      <description>Social Psychology: Characteristics, Motives, and Situationism
PSYCH/550
May 27, 2013
Social Psychology: Characteristics, Motives, and Situationism
According to Fiske (2010), the classic definition of social psychology is, “the scientific attempt to explain how the thoughts, feelings, and behaviors of individuals are influenced by the actual, imagined, or implied presence of other human beings” [ (p. 4) ]. In other words, where general psychology is the study of human behavior on an individual level, social psychology is the study of human behavior in a social context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Music on Psychology and Behavior Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/the-effect-of-music-on-psychology-and-behavior-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 18:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/the-effect-of-music-on-psychology-and-behavior-essay/</guid>
      <description>The Effect of Music on Psychology and Behavior
There have always been discussions of the effects music has on ones behavior, and how it’s related to Psychology. The truth has never really been verified among common knowledge, but it’s usually something that intrigues people. They say heavy metal and rap can make teenagers violent, sad and depressing music can make teenagers sad and depressed, and some say it’s best to listen to classical music when doing schoolwork because it makes your brain more active.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Sport and Exercise Psychology Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/the-importance-of-sport-and-exercise-psychology-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 10:08:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/the-importance-of-sport-and-exercise-psychology-essay/</guid>
      <description>Sport and exercise psychology is a mandatory aspect of the sport science discipline. This discipline contributes to the various professional practices associated with physical activities such as - teaching of physical education, recreation and health promotion, and kinesiology related professions - because it plays a mental role for the participants. Sport and exercise psychologists view physical activity in several different ways: physical activity as a tool for health, physical activity as a tool for human potential, and physical activity as a tool for social change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethics in Research Psychology  Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/ethics-in-research-psychology-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 02:08:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/ethics-in-research-psychology-essay/</guid>
      <description>What is ethics?
If one was to ask the question, “What do ethics mean to you?” These responses would be likely to follow. “Ethics is what my feelings tell me is right or wrong.” “Ethics have to do with my religious beliefs.” “Being ethical means following the laws.” Those replies would be expected. Many do relate ethics with their feelings, but it is not a matter of following feelings. In fact, we will often times stray from living ethically if we were guided by our feelings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Diverse Nature of Psychology Essay examples</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/the-diverse-nature-of-psychology-essay-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 18:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/the-diverse-nature-of-psychology-essay-examples/</guid>
      <description>The Diverse Nature of Psychology
The American Psychological Association has identified 54 divisions within the field of psychology (Plante, 2011). Each division has stemmed from one of the seven major perspectives: psychodynamic, behavioral, humanistic, cognitive, sociocultural, biological, and evolutionary. This diversity within psychology, allows psychologists the ability to expand in all areas of explanation, assessment, and diagnoses, which furthers the science of psychology through many different subfield specialties.
Influence on Psychology’s Major Concepts Diversity is off great influence on the major concepts in psychology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inconsistent and Consistent Information in the Psychology of Stereotypical Behavior</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/inconsistent-and-consistent-information-in-the-psychology-of-stereotypical-behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 10:05:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/inconsistent-and-consistent-information-in-the-psychology-of-stereotypical-behavior/</guid>
      <description>Inconsistent and Consistent Information in the Psychology of Stereotypical Behavior.
The theoretical and practical implications of inconsistent and consistent information in the Psychology of Stereotypical Behavior differentiates in two ways. With consistent information, a group is known for certain behaviors (negative or positive), and the subject who is analyzing the behavior may lose interest since the known behavior is consistent with the stereotype. However, when a group shows inconsistencies of the perceived stereotypical behaviors, then the analyzer will question the inconsistencies, and give specific attention to the group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Career Research Paper: Clinical Psychology</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/career-research-paper-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 02:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/career-research-paper-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Career Research Paper: Clinical Psychology
Clinical psychology is just one of the many subfields that psychology has to offer. Those who choose to enter clinical psychology aim to help people with addiction, emotional stress, mental illness, or any other type of mental problems. Knowing what a clinical psychologist does in their practice is important in understanding their profession. A clinical psychologist&amp;rsquo;s education is the most prominent part of their career; without it, they cannot be considered a psychologist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religion and Psychology Essay example</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/religion-and-psychology-essay-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 18:03:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/religion-and-psychology-essay-example/</guid>
      <description>Religious faith is important to most Americans, with approximately 95% of Americans reporting belief in God and about 50% being active in church organizations (Gallup &amp;amp; Castelli, 1989). Despite the widespread prevalence of religious beliefs in society, some researchers have maintained that religion and religious beliefs are often neglected in psychological research (Jones, 1994; Plante, 1996). This neglect stems from a couple of different factors. First, it is difficult for psychologists to overcome the fact that believers in many religions claim to have unique access to the truth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethics in Psychology Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/ethics-in-psychology-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 10:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/ethics-in-psychology-essay/</guid>
      <description>Ethics in Psychology
Our country was founded on certain moral principles. The moral principles which guide our lives are referred to as ethics. These ethics have an impact on how we interact with the world around us and shape our personalities; this happens even if we do not realize their immediate impact. It is for this very reason that ethics in psychological research became necessary. “One may also define ethics as a method, procedure, or perspective for deciding how to act and for analyzing complex problems and issues” (Resnik, 2011).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychology and Human Behavior  Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/psychology-and-human-behavior-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 02:01:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/psychology-and-human-behavior-essay/</guid>
      <description>Psychology and Human Behavior What makes people behave the way they do? Can anyone analyse 12 billion brain cells to determine how and why the mind functions the way it does?How is it that people being similar in physiological terms, are yet so different in psychological terms?
Man has a multiple nature,there is a constant conflict…between good &amp;amp; evil, between the urges &amp;amp; restricting forces, between thoughts &amp;amp; feelings, head &amp;amp; heart, soul &amp;amp; body,lower nature &amp;amp; upper nature, The book says Yes!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nick Carraway the Perfect Narrator for the Great Gatsby Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/nick-carraway-the-perfect-narrator-for-the-great-gatsby-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 16:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/nick-carraway-the-perfect-narrator-for-the-great-gatsby-essay/</guid>
      <description>Nick Carraway, The Perfect Narrator Nick Carraway is a prime example of how an unbiased and trustworthy narrator can change a book. The Great Gatsby by F. Scott Fitzgerald is told in first person point of view, through the eyes of Nick Carraway, a 30-year-old man living in West Egg, New York. Carraway tells the story as it is happening and lets the reader know what is to come. Nick seems to be an “invisible character” because he is involved in the story but not in the major conflict.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relationships in the Great Gatsby</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/relationships-in-the-great-gatsby/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 08:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/relationships-in-the-great-gatsby/</guid>
      <description>It is an idealistic vision of absolute success that can be found in America. Many men in the 1920s dreamed of attaining large amounts of money by owning businesses or trading stocks. Women, however, had to come from a wealthy family or marry a rich business man. F. Scott Fitzgerald explored this concept in his famous novel The Great Gatsby.
The Great Gatsby chronicles the events of one fateful summer in 1922s New York.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Gatsby and the American Dream</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/the-great-gatsby-and-the-american-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/the-great-gatsby-and-the-american-dream/</guid>
      <description>The American Dream is a huge achievement that everyone wants to reach. Whether people want to admit it or not, it is a symbol all it’s self. It can be anything really, a great job, a family, white picket fence, even music or attending concerts of your favorite band. The American Dream is something that makes you so happy and what you can achieve or want achieve in your lifetime. The main AMerican Dream is money, a family, and happiness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Gatsby Thesis</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/great-gatsby-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 16:20:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/great-gatsby-thesis/</guid>
      <description>Thesis: The pursuit of the American Dream is a dominant theme throughout The Great Gatsby, which is carried out in various ways by F. Scott Fitzgerald, how the author represents this theme through his characters and their actions is one small aspect of it.
Fitzgerald&amp;rsquo;s dominant theme in The Great Gatsby focuses on the corruption of the American Dream. By analyzing high society during the1920s through the eyes of narrator Nick Carraway, the author reveals that the American Dream has transformed from a pure ideal of security into a convoluted scheme of materialistic power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nick and his Experiences of Materialism in ;The Great Gatsby;</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/nick-and-his-experiences-of-materialism-in-the-great-gatsby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 08:19:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/nick-and-his-experiences-of-materialism-in-the-great-gatsby/</guid>
      <description>The Great Gatsby shows the ambition of one man&amp;rsquo;s achievement of his goal, the disappointment of failing, and the hopelessness of it. During the era of this novel, which is around the 1920&amp;rsquo;s, America was a country with huge misery, ambition, and lack of humanity values. The novel shows a reflection of this decade, it illustrates the burning passion one man has toward his objective and the different aspects of the American principles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Gatsby Research: Gatsby Is Considered a Christ Figure</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/the-great-gatsby-research-gatsby-is-considered-a-christ-figure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/the-great-gatsby-research-gatsby-is-considered-a-christ-figure/</guid>
      <description>A Christ figure is depicted as a visionary character who is symbolic to Jesus Christ and suggests towards the beginning of the novel, the reader learns more about Gatsby’s early life and can see how he to Biblical stories. In F. Scott Fitzgerald’s The Great Gatsby, the intriguing and mysterious character Jay Gatsby is undoubtedly represented as a Christ figure. Fitzgerald uses strikingly similar characteristics between Gatsby and Jesus, resulting images to the Bible and Gatsby’s ultimate death echoing that of Jesus’ crucifixion to relate Gatsby to Christ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In The Great Gatsby, Nick Carraway as the Foil, Protagonist, and Narrator</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/in-the-great-gatsby-nick-carraway-as-the-foil-protagonist-and-narrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 16:16:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/in-the-great-gatsby-nick-carraway-as-the-foil-protagonist-and-narrator/</guid>
      <description>In The Great Gatsby, written by F. Scott Fitzgerald, Nick Carraway functions as both the foil and protagonist, as well as the narrator. A young man from Minnesota, Nick travels to the West Egg in New York to learn about the bond business. He lives in the district of Long Island, next door to Jay Gatsby, a wealthy young man known for throwing lavish parties every night. Nick is gradually pulled into the lives of the rich socialites of the East and West Egg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Gatsby</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/great-gatsby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 08:15:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/great-gatsby/</guid>
      <description>The Great Gatsby – Study Guide
Chapter 1 1. Why is Nick Carraway made the narrator? The device of giving Nick the function of narrator lends psychic distance from the story. Nick is part of the action, yet he is not one of the principals. He shares some of the emotions and is in a position to interpret those of the others. However, the happens are not center on him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay on  the great gatsby</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-the-great-gatsby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-the-great-gatsby/</guid>
      <description>Fitzgerald’s The Great Gatsby is a novel that explains the conflicts between love, sin, and death. It is a story of love and how love can be quickly lost or hidden beneath the surface. It reveals what people go through in this decade, as well as the novel’s decade. There are conflicts throughout the novel of lust, sin, and pure evil. It basically explains the way the human mind operates when the heart is completely and undeniably in love with another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Gatsby Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/great-gatsby-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 16:12:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/great-gatsby-essay/</guid>
      <description>The novel The Great Gatsby is a story that takes place in the 1920’s. The story tells about Nick Carraway moving to New York and the actions that take place during his time in New York. The two main characters of the story are Nick
Carraway who moved to New York and the other main character is Jay Gatsby who is Nicks new neboir and a very rich man who always has parties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay on The Great Gatsby</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-the-great-gatsby-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 08:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-the-great-gatsby-2/</guid>
      <description>In Class Essay
To what extent is The Great Gatsby a moral novel. Discuss.
The society our nation lives in today has developed morals and principles through the lessons experienced from the past. The Roaring Twenties was a time of change and a chance to pave a path for the person you wanted to become. Morals and principles served as guidelines rather than rules and were merely preached that practiced. Thus, the severity of the immoral actions taking place created opportunities for lessons to be learned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Gatsby Character Analysis: Nick Carraway Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/great-gatsby-character-analysis-nick-carraway-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:11:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/great-gatsby-character-analysis-nick-carraway-essay/</guid>
      <description>West meets East&amp;hellip; and Doesn’t Like it.
The novel The Great Gatsby is an interesting tale of two cities really. Nick Carraway; the narrator, represents all that is good an wholesome in the great midwest. He is a well-educated man who aspires to be a bond broker. His character is conflicted internally and externally throughout the novel but really culminates into a loathing for all things eastern. Carraway’s farmboy charm and doe-eyed innocence is put to the test when he meets The Great Jay Gatsby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Gatsby Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/the-great-gatsby-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 16:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/the-great-gatsby-essay/</guid>
      <description>The Great Gatsby and Today &amp;rsquo;s Society
In American society, the way people act is quite an interesting, yet confusing subject to look at. If you were to look closely at the behavior and the thinking of the average American man in the modern day, you would see that he is not too different from a man that lived one hundred years ago in America. Obviously many things have changed in society that make a man different nowadays compared to one hundred years ago, but the point is that, in general, the mind of an American person has kept the same characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Gatsby by F.Scott Fitzgerald</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/the-great-gatsby-by-f-scott-fitzgerald/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 08:07:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/the-great-gatsby-by-f-scott-fitzgerald/</guid>
      <description>An unreliable narrator is a narrator, who, has little to no credibility and simply cannot be trusted. These narrators are often in first-person and “seem to have limited knowledge, to be mistaken in his or her understanding of people and events, or even to be deliberately misleading the reader.” (Margree par. 1). The well-known novel The Great Gatsby by Scott Fitzgerald, introduces readers to a story where everything may not be necessarily true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay on The Lessons of The Great Gatsby</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-the-lessons-of-the-great-gatsby/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 00:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/essay-on-the-lessons-of-the-great-gatsby/</guid>
      <description>“The Great Gatsby” is a novel written by F. Scott Fitzgerald in the 1920’s. The novel is narrated by a young man named Nick Carraway, who moves to West Egg, New York to learn more about the bond business so he can eventually sell bonds. He moves into an average house in between two huge mansions, so in comparison his average house looks like a small, run down shack. One of the owners of those mansions, and Carraway’s new neighbor, is Jay Gatsby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Materialism - The Great Gatsby Essay</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/materialism-the-great-gatsby-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 16:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/materialism-the-great-gatsby-essay/</guid>
      <description>Materialism
America has been labeled &amp;ldquo;The land of opportunity,&amp;rdquo; a place where it is possible to accomplish anything and everything. This state of mind is known as &amp;ldquo;The American Dream.&amp;rdquo; The American Dream provides a sense of hope and faith that looks forward to the fulfillment of human wishes and desires. This dream, however, originates from a desire for spiritual and material improvement. Unfortunately, the acquisition of material has been tied together with happiness in America.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>F. Scott Fitzgerald’s The Great Gatsby - Nick Carraway as Narrator</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/f-scott-fitzgeralds-the-great-gatsby-nick-carraway-as-narrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 08:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/f-scott-fitzgeralds-the-great-gatsby-nick-carraway-as-narrator/</guid>
      <description>The narrative point of view adopted by F. Scott Fitzgerald in The Great Gatsby supports the novel&amp;rsquo;s criticism of the upper class and the importance of wealth in society. Fitzgerald uses Nick Carraway as the narrator who views the upper class as entirely superficial. Through his observation of people at Gatsby&amp;rsquo;s party, at the beginning of chapter three, Nick seems to feel that the wealthy are clones of a stereotype accepted and created by themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Character of Nick Carraway in The Great Gatsby Essays</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/the-character-of-nick-carraway-in-the-great-gatsby-essays/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/the-character-of-nick-carraway-in-the-great-gatsby-essays/</guid>
      <description>The novel begins with Nick Carraway, a young man from Minnesota and the narrator od this novel, moves to New York in the summer of 1922 to learn more about bond business. He rents a house in the West Egg district of Long Island, a wealthy but fashionable area populated by the newly rich. Nick&amp;rsquo;s next door neighbor is mysteroius man named Jay Gatsby, who lives in Gothic mansion and throws lavish parties every Saturday night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crooked Carraway from The Great Gatsby by F. Scott Fitzgerald</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/crooked-carraway-from-the-great-gatsby-by-f-scott-fitzgerald/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 16:02:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/crooked-carraway-from-the-great-gatsby-by-f-scott-fitzgerald/</guid>
      <description>Nick Carraway from The Great Gatsby is not honest in the way he depicts other characters and feels the need to intensely assert his honesty in order to place himself above the other characters in the book. Nick tries to be neutral by being “Inclined to reserve all judgments”(1). He is found to emit information that could give the reader a better perspective to the story. Nick Carraway tells the story by putting himself in a better light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nick Carraway as Honest Liar in Fitzgerald&#39;s The Great Gatsby</title>
      <link>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/nick-carraway-as-honest-liar-in-fitzgeralds-the-great-gatsby/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 08:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.fornit.kiev.ua/post/nick-carraway-as-honest-liar-in-fitzgeralds-the-great-gatsby/</guid>
      <description>Nick Carraway as Honest Liar in Fitzgerald&amp;rsquo;s The Great Gatsby
&amp;ldquo;Everyone suspects himself of at least one of the cardinal virtues, and this is mine: I am one of the few honest people that I have ever known&amp;rdquo; (Fitzgerald Gatsby 64). So writes Nick Carraway in F. Scott Fitzgerald&amp;rsquo;s The Great Gatsby, characterizing himself in opposition to the great masses of humanity as a perfectly honest man. The honesty that Nick attributes to himself must be a nearly perfect one, by dint of both its rarity and its &amp;ldquo;cardinal&amp;rdquo; nature; Nick asserts for himself that he is among the most honest people he has ever encountered.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>